<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE ditacomponent PUBLIC "-//XMETAL//DTD DITA Component//EN" "ditacomponent.dtd">
<ditacomponent id="ditacomponent_FA3BC214FC444EF78140A33698A4AAF4"><description>e_Contribs,Acks</description><compbody><reusable-content><section id="section_EF3FC16912464FD9B49F97DDB9F4D630">
				<title>Contributors and Acknowledgments</title>
				<p><b>Contributors:</b> National Center for Supercomputing Applications
        (NCSA) at the University of Illinois, Fortner Software, Unidata Program Center
        (netCDF), The Independent JPEG Group (JPEG), Jean-loup Gailly and Mark Adler
        (gzip), and Digital Equipment Corporation (DEC). 
      </p>
				<p><b>Acknowledgments:</b> Portions of HDF5 were developed with support
        from the University of California, Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory (UC
        LLNL). The following statement applies to those portions of the product and
        must be retained in any redistribution of source code, binaries, documentation,
        and/or accompanying materials: 
      </p>
				<ul id="ul_A60168385F174C29B20AE09EF96E84EB">
					<li id="li_583DC5F82D7E42CBBE5877CB70656D40">This work was partially
          produced at the University of California, Lawrence Livermore National
          Laboratory (UC LLNL) under contract no. W-7405-ENG-48 (Contract 48) between the
          U.S. Department of Energy (DOE) and The Regents of the University of California
          (University) for the operation of UC LLNL. 
        </li>
					<li id="li_A3EE27198FED46709841DE7F2091DF53"><b>DISCLAIMER:</b> This
          work was prepared as an account of work sponsored by an agency of the United
          States Government. Neither the United States Government nor the University of
          California nor any of their employees, makes any warranty, express or implied,
          or assumes any liability or responsibility for the accuracy, completeness, or
          usefulness of any information, apparatus, product, or process disclosed, or
          represents that its use would not infringe privately- owned rights. Reference
          herein to any specific commercial products, process, or service by trade name,
          trademark, manufacturer, or otherwise, does not necessarily constitute or imply
          its endorsement, recommendation, or favoring by the United States Government or
          the University of California. The views and opinions of authors expressed
          herein do not necessarily state or reflect those of the United States
          Government or the University of California, and shall not be used for
          advertising or product endorsement purposes.
        </li>
				</ul>
			</section></reusable-content></compbody></ditacomponent>
